questions = [{'question': 'What type of communication does the Jakarta Messaging API enable?', 'choices': ['Reliable, asynchronous, loosely coupled communication.', 'Secure, synchronous communication based on the HTTP protocol.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'What is the annotation that identifies a POJO as a REST web service?', 'choices': ['@Stateless', '@Path', '@Inject'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'When validating a bean using validate(), what is returned?', 'choices': ['The return from validate() method is the Java Set of ConstraintViolation violations.', 'We need to handle exceptions that may be thrown to find out about constraint violations.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'Which statement about Bean Validation API is false?', 'choices': ['Bean Validation can only be used with Jakarta Faces (JSF).', 'A new validation constraint can be formed from other constraints.', 'Custom validation constraints can be defined.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'What is the favourite JSF page description language?', 'choices': ['JSP (.jsp files)', 'Facelets (.xhtml files)'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'Which statement about a servlet is true?', 'choices': ['A servlet is a Java class used to dynamically create a response within a web container.', 'A servlet is just a Jakarta EE interface for implementing dynamic behaviour.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'Which statement about JSF is true?', 'choices': ['There is only one implementation of JSF developed by Oracle.', 'Jakarta Faces is built on the Model-View-Controller design pattern.'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'Jakarta EE uses Programming by Exception, which means...', 'choices': ['It is not necessary to define most behaviours using metadata.', "It's a programming style that relies on Java exception handling to enable specific processing."], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'What is the role of Jakarta EE containers?', 'choices': ['They act as archive-type envelopes for components.', 'They offer technical services to the components deployed in them.'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'What is the role of CDI?', 'choices': ['CDI is not part of Jakarta EE.', 'CDI defines a standard set of component management services for the Jakarta EE platform.', 'CDI only describes dependency relationships between components.'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'Which statement about EJBs is true?', 'choices': ['EJBs are server components that encapsulate the business logic of a Jakarta EE application.', 'EJBs are server components that implement technical issues of Jakarta EE.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'Which statement about REST or JAX-RS is true?', 'choices': ['JAX-RS is a specification of the Jakarta EE platform for developing REST services.', 'REST is a specification of Jakarta EE.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'What is the role of @Target in a custom annotation?', 'choices': ['Make the annotation available in the Java bytecode.', 'Designate the elements to which the annotation can be applied.'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'Which statement about EntityManager is false?', 'choices': ['Thanks to the EntityManager, you can create query type requests.', 'The EntityManager allows CRUD operations.', 'In Jakarta EE, you must explicitly create an instance of an EntityManager linked to a persistence unit.'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'Which statement about @Inject is true?', 'choices': ['@Inject can only be used to inject resources from the application server.', '@Inject can be used on an attribute whose type is an interface.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'Which statement about Eclipse MicroProfile is true?', 'choices': ['MicroProfile is the name of a profile in the Jakarta EE specification.', 'MicroProfile offers a set of APIs focused on Cloud application development.'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'How to bind a Jakarta Faces (JSF) page to a CDI bean instance?', 'choices': ['The Expression Language (EL) with #{...}', 'Injecting dependencies into the page.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'Can entities be automatically synchronized in JPA?', 'choices': ['False', 'True'], 'answer': 1}, {'question': 'Which assertion about JPA is false?', 'choices': ['JPA does not support native SQL queries.', 'JPA is used with relational databases.', 'JPA includes an Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) mechanism.'], 'answer': 0}, {'question': 'Which statement about SOAP is true?', 'choices': ['A SOAP client must be written in the same language as the service.', 'SOAP is an interoperable XML-based technology.'], 'answer': 1}]